Hello friends, welcome to Shiv's
YouTube channel. Here you
get to see informative and knowledgeable videos related to insurance.
Friends, if you are new to the channel, then
first subscribe to the channel so that
notifications of new insurance-related videos reach you first.
Friends, the topic of our today's video is
due to the clean reaction of the insurance policy. In today's video, I will
tell you that even after taking out a life insurance policy,
when the victim dies, the
reasoning request given by his/her claimant is
rejected by the insurance company.
And what are the instruments on which
insurance companies have some authority to
reject the claim, that is, they can
refuse to pay the claim. Friends,
watch the entire video to get complete information. Do not skip anywhere because incomplete does not mean
anything. So friends, let's
start today's video. The
decision to take out life insurance is very important for every person. It is
decided to protect your family from financial crisis in your absence. But sometimes,
upon the death of the insured person, the
claim is rejected by the concerned life insurance company.
Even after filing a complaint, the decision does not come in the insurance company's favor.
At the end of this entire process, the nominee
feels cheated by the insurance company.
Every person who buys life insurance thinks that
after his/her death, in his/her absence, the
insurance company will pay the
amount to the nominee appointed by him/her under the guarantee act. And most of the arguments are true.
But here I
want to clarify one thing that
having life insurance itself does not guarantee getting a clean amount. In
fact,
getting or rejecting a claim
depends on the cause of death. Generally,
after insurance, when someone dies due to any disease
or accidental death, the
insurance company gives a clean chit to the insurance company on natural basis.
However, as per the rules, insurance companies are
not bound to give a clean chit on every type of date. When a
claim is rejected due to lack of information, the
person feels that this rule has been
made today so that the claim can be rejected.
In reality, all life insurance
companies have to follow the rules of the government body IRDA,
and
all these rules have been made by that body.  In
fact, life insurance doesn't cover all kinds of
risks.
In most cases, it's the mistakes made by the insured that are the
cause of the negative reaction.
Generally, after taking out life insurance, the
insured thinks that he has
accomplished an important task and becomes
relaxed thinking this. However, the
second most
important task for taking out life insurance is to understand the terms
and conditions of the policy and what is included in it and
explain it to his policyholder so that the
policyholder doesn't have to worry in times of need.
So friends, let's find out under what
circumstances a life insurance company
rejects a claim. Number one: If the insured
person drives after drinking alcohol or under the influence of any other intoxicant
and as a result, an accident occurs
and he dies in it,
his claim will be rejected.
Number two: If the insured person is
murdered or if there is suspicion of murder, the claim will
not be passed until he is acquitted.
Number three: In case of death due to natural disasters
like earthquake, tsunami, etc., the claim is
rejected.
However, a separate loan can be taken for its cover.
Number four: If a
person dies in a terrorist attack, the
claim is rejected.
Number 5: If the insured person has already been
involved in criminal activities and is
murdered for this reason, the
claim is also rejected. Number 6: A claim request is rejected even if someone dies while
participating in life-threatening sports, such as car racing,
bike racing, or performing any other stunt on the road.
Number
7: A claim is rejected even if someone dies due to breaking the law.
Number 80: A
claim is also rejected if someone dies due to consuming tobacco products.
If a person consumes alcohol or tobacco
products, they must
inform the insurance company about it at the time of purchasing the policy.
Generally, the only
difference between insurance policies for non-addicts and addicts is that an
additional premium is charged from the addict,
and this is also
covered under their policy. However, if the insured
initially hides this fact and does not
disclose it, and later the
cause of death is revealed to be alcohol and tobacco,
then in that case,  The claim on his policy will be
rejected. This number 90 is
if the medical history, family
information and lifestyle are hidden, that is,
given incorrectly, then if the
cause of death
turns out to be a hidden chronic disease, then the
claim will be rejected. This
number 10 is if the policy has lapsed and the
person has stopped paying the premium on it
and if someone takes it later, then the
claim on that too gets rejected. Number 11 is
if a friend commits suicide, then
some companies do not give any clearance for one or two years
but after that they take it.
So friends, these are the reasons due to which
life insurance companies
reject such estimated claims. Although such cases are
rare, in many of these
cases, the insured makes many mistakes before or after the death due to which the
claim gets rejected.
Apart from all these reasons, the rest of the claims are
easily passed on the date of death.
Therefore,
while taking insurance, always give correct information about your and your
family's medical history and your habits to the company so that
in your absence, a claim can be made normally.  But the
plane request can be passed easily. I
hope you liked the information given by me. To
watch more videos related to insurance,
use the link given in the description below.
If you liked the video, then there
is only one way to tell this, for that
like the video and share it with friends
and if you want to ask something then comment. So,
thanks for watching this video completely. See you
in the new video on Saturday with a new topic.